# Erik Hirsch

Apple Valley, CA 92308
Phone: 760 420-4308 | Email: ehirsch760@gmail.com
LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/e-hirsch | GitHub: github.com/eh4git

Portfolio: eh4git.github.io/React Profile

#### Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with previous management experience and a passion for problem solving and collaboration. Effectively communicates with others to streamline the development cycle to produce polished applications. Known by peers for having a strong work ethic and being determined to produce the highest quality results possible.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6

Technologies: Node, React, React Native, Redux, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose,

Express, jQuery, BootStrap, Semantic, Materialize, Handlebars.js, Ajax, Sass

#### **Projects**

# Once Upon An Adventure - July 2020

www.onceuaa.com | github.com/eh4git/once-upon-an-adventure

A collection of educational mini games within an RPG style browser game.

- Polished Bootstrap UI allows users to customize and control a character's movement.
- JavaScript and canvas html elements utilized in the creation of educational mini games.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Implemented React for the front end UI incorporating hooks and Redux to manage state.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles Ajax requests.
- Secured user accounts implement bcrypt to hash and salt passwords.

**Key Role(s):** Animation of sprites, music, and sound effects

**Technologies:** JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Howler, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Redux

# Story Time - June 2020

github.com/eh4git/StoryTime | fathomless-waters-70908.herokuapp.com Personalized children's story generator.

- Responsive Bootstrap UI allows users to easily navigate while using the application.
- Developed front end logic using ¡Query.
- Integrates MongoDB to provide data persistence.
- Node and Express used to create back end logic that handles requests.
- Secured user accounts implement brrypt to hash and salt passwords.

Key Role(s): HTML, JavaScript, Front end logic

Technologies: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, ¡Query, Ajax, MongoDB, Express, Node

### YouMDb - May 2020

github.com/eh4git/YouMDb-Movie-App | eh4git.github.io/YouMDb-Movie-App/ Movie information search and recommendations web application.

- Integrates local storage to provide data persistence.
- jQuery is used to make Ajax requests to APIs and render html.
- Implements iframe HTML elements to embed YouTube movie trailer videos.
- HTML layout utilizes Bootstrap to create a responsive web application.

**Key Role(s):** Bootstrap HTML layout and CSS

Technologies: Ajax, Express, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

#### Experience

**Enumerator** 2020 - Present

#### **US Department of Commerce - Bureau Of Census**

Victorville, CA

- Strong communication skills used to engage and connect with the public.
- Work 100% independently to complete daily tasks.
- Responsibly handle sensitive materials to ensure privacy law requirements are met.

**Delivery Driver** 2019 - 2020 **United Parcel Service** Victorville, CA

- Worked independently while managing time efficiently.
  - Recognized for strong work ethic.

Awarded by management for achieving highest performance on multiple occasions.

# Project Manager 2015 - 2019

#### **Rick Kittson Hardwood Flooring**

Irvine, CA

- Supervised a small team to maintain quality and to complete projects in a timely manner.
- Recognized for strong work ethic.
- Provided training when necessary.
- Secured materials required to complete projects.

#### Cooling Operator 2017 - 2018

#### Golden Island

Rancho Cucamonga, CA

- Reduced labor costs by 50% through assisting in the implementation of new cooling systems and procedures.
- Attained recognition for excellent attendance record.

#### Education

UCLA Extension - Los Angeles, CA

#### **Full Stack Web Development - Certificate**

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & React.

Victor Valley College - Victorville, CA

**Management Certificate of Completion - Certificate** 

31 Unit program that teaches the skills that are required for management. Courses included Accounting, Economics, Computer Literacy, Human Resource Management, Legal Environment of Business, Business Math, and Business Communications.